<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Dmitry Avtonomov</title>
    <link>localhost/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Dmitry Avtonomov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016-present Dmitry Avtonomov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="localhost/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring back &#34;Open command window here&#34; context menu item in Windows</title>
      <link>localhost/post/2018-06-27-command-prompt-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/post/2018-06-27-command-prompt-here/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a simple registry hack.
 Strat registry editor: Run -&amp;gt; regedit. Go to HKEY_CLASSES_ROOT\Directory\shell\cmd. Right-click the cmd (folder) key, and click Permissions. Click the Advanced button. Advanced Security Settings dialog will open, at the top next to Owner click Change. Put in your account name, click Check Names to make sure domain etc is set up correctly, click OK. Check the Replace owner on subcontainers and objects check box near Owner field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using multiple different shells/subsystems on Windows</title>
      <link>localhost/post/2018-03-07-shells-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/post/2018-03-07-shells-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>Shells to be used:
 cmd.exe MINGW from Git Cygwin Optionally MSYS2  All of the above are managed through one shell manager - ConEmu.
First install all the shells, then ConEmu.
Easy installation of useful dev tools Use scoop to install basic utilities and languages. Install from powershell (without admin rights):
Set-ExecutionPolicy RemoteSigned -scope CurrentUser iex (new-object net.webclient).downloadstring(&#39;https://get.scoop.sh&#39;)  Using command scoop export you can get an importable list of all installed packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving problems with tethering wifi from an Android phone</title>
      <link>localhost/post/2018-02-19-tethering-wifi-from-android-dns-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>localhost/post/2018-02-19-tethering-wifi-from-android-dns-problems/</guid>
      <description>Once I tried to connect from Win10 to a hotspot running off Google Pixel 2 (Android 8.1.0) connected to T-Mobile (tethering) and it worked for a while, but one day it just broke. Connection would work for 5-10 seconds allowing to load one website maybe, but then it threw some DNS errors. Setting DNS server manually didn&amp;rsquo;t help, also ping 8.8.8.8 timed out.
The solution (from elevated cmd prompt):
netsh int ip reset c:\resetlog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>