<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random pieces of information on Dmitry Avtonomov</title>
    <link>https://chhh.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random pieces of information on Dmitry Avtonomov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Dmitry Avtonomov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chhh.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using multiple different shells/subsystems on Windows</title>
      <link>https://chhh.github.io/post/2018-03-07-shells-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chhh.github.io/post/2018-03-07-shells-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>Shells to be used:
 cmd.exe MINGW from Git Cygwin Optionally MSYS2  All of the above are managed through one shell manager - ConEmu.
First install all the shells, then ConEmu.
Easy installation of useful dev tools Use scoop to install basic utilities and languages. Install from powershell (without admin rights):
Set-ExecutionPolicy RemoteSigned -scope CurrentUser iex (new-object net.webclient).downloadstring(&#39;https://get.scoop.sh&#39;)  Using command scoop export you can get an importable list of all installed packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tethering WiFi from Android DNS problems</title>
      <link>https://chhh.github.io/post/2018-02-19-tethering-wifi-from-android-dns-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chhh.github.io/post/2018-02-19-tethering-wifi-from-android-dns-problems/</guid>
      <description>So I tried to connect from Win10 to a hotspot running off Google Pixel 2 (Android 8.1.0) connected to T-Mobile (tethering) and it worked for a while, but one day it just broke. Connection would work for 5-10 seconds allowing to load one website maybe, but then it threw some DNS errors. Setting DNS server manually didn&amp;rsquo;t help, also ping 8.8.8.8 timed out.
The solution (from elevated cmd prompt):
netsh int ip reset c:\resetlog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellij IDEA live templates</title>
      <link>https://chhh.github.io/post/2017-01-26-intellij-idea-live-templates-slf4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chhh.github.io/post/2017-01-26-intellij-idea-live-templates-slf4j/</guid>
      <description>Intellij IDEA IDE has a nice feature of live templates. You type several symbols, press tab (by default) and it expands the symbols into full expressions. E.g. you can type fori, press Tab and get a full for loop created for you, or type iter, press Tab and if you have iterables in scope, you&amp;rsquo;ll be presented with a choice of available ones to iterate over.
Slf4j logger in each class It&amp;rsquo;s a super common thing to type at the beginning of each class:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing java libraries to Maven Central</title>
      <link>https://chhh.github.io/post/2017-01-25-publishing-to-maven-central/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chhh.github.io/post/2017-01-25-publishing-to-maven-central/</guid>
      <description>What is Sonatype and why is it needed? Sonatype provides a staging repository, which performs validation and allows to push the builds that pass all checks to the Central repo. Without it, basically, you can&amp;rsquo;t easily publish anything to the Central easily, unless you&amp;rsquo;re an Apache project or similar.
Getting started Follow their getting started guide to set up the needed credentials. This should be easy - you create a JIRA account and you create a ticket in JIRA to claim your namespace (groupId in Maven terms).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>